Delmwin Baeka

(+1) 431-792-3284

dbaekajnr@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/delmwinb/ 20 Continental Close, Roman Ridge, Ghana

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with experience leading development teams, building profit generating products across the globe for successful companies with key products processing almost \$1 billion in transactions in the fintech and insurance tech space. Professional experience delivering amazing customer-first products for mobile and web applications using frameworks and tools, such as VueJS, Laravel, Golang, Swift, in a team-based environment. Projects Link: https://dbaeka.com/projects_summary.pdf (non-confidential)

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: PHP, Golang, JavaScript, Swift, C/C++, Python,
- Infrastructure/DevOps: Git, Unix, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes (k8s), Amazon Web Services (AWS), Bash, JIRA, Vault, Gitlab (repo, CI/CD), Vercel, RabbitMQ, Helm
- Frameworks: Laravel, VueJS, Django, Flutter, OpenGL, Flask, FastAPI
- Databases/Storage: MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS S3, Redis, DynamoDB, MongoDB
- Additional: Testing (PyTest, PHPUnit, Selenium, Appium), Machine Learning (Keras, pyTorch)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer (Contract)

May 2023 - Present

Buckhill Software • UK/Croatia

- Integrated custom modules and features, leading RabbitMQ development for distributed services and implementing scripts for complex insurance rating processes, enhancing functionality and accuracy.
- Managed development and technical design of two key products, delivering ahead of schedule with over 90% test coverage using CI/CD pipelines.
- Maintained coding standards, provided feedback from code reviews within the team, and led backend engineer candidate reviews, resulting in two successful hires.
- Implemented Sentry and OpenTelemetry with Grafana and Loki, proactively speeding time to resolving backend exceptions.
- Led EAV database pivot for ETL, applied graph algorithms for schema reconciliation, and ensured seamless CI/CD integration, boosting performance and client satisfaction.

Skills: Laravel, Golang, MySQL, Docker, Git, AWS, Testing, k8s

Managing Director

Sep 2022 - Present

Lidel Company Limited • Ghana

- Implemented innovative operational processes, enhancing efficiency and reducing costs by 20%. Successfully directed day-to-day operations, ensuring seamless workflow and resource optimization
- Orchestrated the development and execution of a comprehensive strategic plan, aligning organizational objectives with a forward-looking vision

Technology Manager/Lead Software Engineer (Software Engineering)

Jul 2021 - Aug 2022

Zeepay • Accra, Ghana

- Documented technical requirements for expansion of products into 4 new markets, and executed generated plans in timely manner that saw Zeepay grow from Ghana to multiple countries including Zambia, Barbados, UK and Cote d'Ivoire within a year
- Spearheaded and led software development projects with MoneyGram, Ria, Remitly and others to improve remittance redemption across Africa, US and the Caribbean, contributing to an increase in profitability by over 50% for 2021
- Mentored and coordinated a team of 4 software and QA engineers to manage, develop and support all products, helping 2 developers move from the graduate program to full-time developers
- Co-ordinated walkthroughs and meetings weekly with an average of 5 clients to set expectations and milestones, and discuss specifications, costs, and processes

Technology Specialist (Software Engineering)

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

Zeepay • Accra, Ghana

- Optimized the performance of existing Payment Gateway processor and Mobile Money platform through code refactoring,
 SQL and infrastructure optimizations leading to uptime of more than 99.5% uptime and solving recurring downtime issues
- Maintained and implemented change requests and bug fixes for assigned products, exceeding 100% KPI goals for velocity,

- stability and burndown
- Engineered architecture and code for mobile money platform on USSD and WhatsApp bot that supports more than 1 million active users in Ghana with an uptime of 99.50% and latency less than 300ms
- Instituted the use of elastic (ELK) and python scripts for improved log management, observability and application performance monitoring which helped quantify key metrics and influenced a 99.5% uptime of services to clients

Technology Analyst (Integrations)

Feb 2021 - Feb 2021

Zeepay • Accra, Ghana

- Standardized the use of continuous delivery/continuous integration CI/CD pipelines to improve the development-release cycle by more than 200%
- Integrated third party payment services into existing multi-payment service gateway improving payment conversion rate by 2% to 97%

Lead Software Engineer

Jun 2018 - Aug 2020

Rook+ • Accra, Ghana

 Developed and launched main application for mobile using Swift and Flutter and the web in PHP with an average 1000 active student users in the first month

Student Software Developer

Sep 2019 - Jan 2020

VMware • Shanghai, China

- Conducted pair programming and code reviews of project team of 5 developers to integrate pull requests into main project code
- Conceptualized and coded CloudTides platform to support running volunteer backgrounds in less than 1 second when resource usage falls below configurable value using Django/Golang backend, React.js frontend and kubernetes infrastructure

EDUCATION

BSc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sep 2016 - Aug 2020

Shanghai Jiao Tong University Joint Institute • Shanghai, China University of Michigan Ann Arbor Joint Institute • Ann Arbor, United States

Awards: SJTU Outstanding Graduate, International Student Scholarship Award, Dean's List

CERTIFICATIONS

- Machine Learning (Coursera) Credential ID: <u>YWBCVZF5YQWD</u>
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning (Coursera) Credential ID: 89WVCXMAX7VG

AWARDS AND HONOURS

2021 Ghana Club 100 (Zeepay)

Awarded officially number 1 company in Ghana for the year under leadership of the tech team

2021 Ultimate Team Player of the Year (Zeepay)

Awarded to employee who contributes and executes diligently during assigned team task and always offers a helping hand